Francis Biddle Collection of International Military Tribunal Nuremberg Trial Documents and Related Material
Francis Biddle Collection of International Military Tribunal Nuremberg Trial Documents and Related Material
- Additions
  - Trial documents
    - Memoranda, 1946 Jun-Sep; 11 items (Box 19)
      "Memorandum of Soviet Member [I.T. Nikitchenko] of International Military Tribunal," translated from the Russian; typescript copy, 5 pp.; August 14, 1946
      "Memorandum on the Nazi regime in Germany" probably by Francis Biddle; typescript, 5 pp., and typescript copy, 5 pp.; September 2, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe, Jr. to Judge Biddle on the Schacht, Speer and von Schirach verdicts; typescript, 1 p.; September 17, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe, Jr. to Judge Biddle urging that the opinion state that the findings are based only on the record of available evidence; typescript, 1 p.; September 17, 1946
      Memorandum by James H. Rowe, Jr. to Judge Biddle on a breach of security, "...the most incredible thing that has happened in an incredible year."; typescript, 1 p.; undated
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1946 (Box 19)
      Notes on Glueck and the Pact of Paris; annotated typescript, 3pp.; May 23, 1946
      Transcript in English of a letter from Konrad Weidinger, a cabinet-maker, to Francis Biddle; August 1, 1946
      Notes on the definition of conspiracy; typescript, [4] pp.; August 8, 1946
      "Order for Disciplinary Punishment issued against Attorney Ludwig Babel, 15 Dahlmannstrasse, Nuernberg" in an English translation; typescript copy, 18 pp., with a copy of the covering letter; August 16, 1946
    - Miscellaneous documents, undated (Box 19)
      Biddle, Francis, dissent on the guilty verdict against Admiral Karl Doenitz on Counts Two and Three; typescript copy, 6 pp., A note in Judge Biddle's hand states, "This was not filed. Probably suggested by Parker."; undated
      Birkett, Norman, "The common plan or conspiracy."; typescript copy, 4 pp.; undated
      ? Birkett, Norman, [notes on a draft]; typescript, 4 pp.; undated
      De Vabres, Donnedieu, "Note regarding the speech for the defence by Professor Jahrreiss."; typescript annotated by Judge Biddle, 16 pp.; undated
      "Note [sur] la qualification de complot."; typescript, 3 pp.; same text, holograph, 3 pp.; undated
      "Remarks on the question of organizations suggested by the speech of Mr. Klefisch."; typescript copy, 12 pp.; undated
      Unidentified fragment; typescript copy, pp. 2-6; undated
- Personal papers - originals
  - Correspondence (folder missing 8/7/2012), 1946; 3 items (Box 19)
    Restricted due to fragility. Please use photocopies in Box 1.
  - Notes on Conference, October 2-November 17, 1945; typescript revised, 45 pp. (Box 19)